MOCH YUDHA RUSDIAN

+62813-1341-0515 | yudharus007@gmail.com | Github | Bandung, ID

SUMMARY

I am a mobile developer and front-end developer with over two years of experience. I have a strong interest and experience in creating and developing Android/iOS mobile applications and websites. My most recent experience has been as a mobile developer using the React Native framework. I have developed the Schoolfess Indonesia and SBM Indonesia websites and have created, developed, and launched the Schoolfess and Halalpedia Applications, which are available for download on both the Play Store and the App Store. I possess problem-solving skills, critical thinking, and effective communication while working. I am highly enthusiastic about learning new technologies and always ready to take on new challenges. I believe that my experience and skills can contribute positively and effectively.

WORK EXPERIENCES

PT. RASTEK INOVASI DIGITAL

Mar 2024 - Present

Full – Time - Mobile Developer

- Developed and maintained the IDMAI Mobile Survey Apps for BAPPENAS, facilitating its use by farmers across Indonesia to enhance agricultural productivity and data collection.
- Collaborated seamlessly with Back-End Developers, UI/UX Designers, Computer Vision experts, and the Project Manager to innovate and develop new features, integrating cutting-edge Machine Learning technology to improve functionality.
- Conducted thorough code evaluations and optimizations, achieving a significant 25% improvement in application performance, enhancing user experience and operational efficiency.
- Performed manual quality assurance to ensure the application runs smoothly and is free of major bugs, guaranteeing a seamless user experience.

PT. HALAL PEDIA INDONESIA

Aug 2023 - November 2023

Full – Time - Mobile Developer

- Performing routine maintenance to ensure that the Halalpedia application runs smoothly and optimally.
- Detecting and fixing bugs that occur in the application quickly and efficiently to enhance the user experience.
- Collaborating closely with the Back-End Developer team and Marketing team to develop and implement new features that will enhance the application's functionality.
- Contribute to developing 5 new features in the Halalpedia application, including the Notification List feature, Inbox feature, Giving Rating to Purchased Items feature, Rating History feature, and Product Discussion feature.
- Responsible for ensuring that the software development kit (SDK) used in application development is always updated to the latest version.
- Conducting regular updates on the Google Play Store and Apple App Store to ensure that users always have access to the latest version with improvements and new features.
- Collaborating with the Quality Assurance team to ensure that every application change or update has been thoroughly tested and meets high-quality standards.

PT. KOMUNITA AMBIS NUSANTARA

Feb 2022 – Aug 2023

Full – Time - Mobile Developer And Front End Developer

- Mentored 4 team internship members. assisting in enhancing their skills, such as teaching UI slicing, API consumption, and providing help when they encounter challenges.
- Responsible for creating, developing, and launching the Android based Schoolfess mobile application.
- Contributed to a 450+ user increase in new downloads within a week after the launch of the Schoolfess application.
- Work closely with UI / UX Designer, Back End Developer, Quality Assurance, and Marketing to create and develop several new features in the Schoolfess App.
- Discuss with the Chief Technology Officer and UI / UX Designer in creating applications to match the functionality and business processes.
- Responsible for the development of the "Schoolfess Indonesia" website, using PHP (Laravel), which includes UI slicing, API consumption, and the addition of new features. Contributed to enhancing UX and user engagement.

• Responsible for the development of the "SBM Indonesia" website, using Javascript (ReactJS), which includes UI slicing, API consumption, updating functionalities, and adding new features to meet user needs.

PT. BAYER INDONESIA

Apr 2020 – Feb 2021

Internship – Full – Stack Web Developer

- Created and developed a web application, the "Employee Performance Management Information System," to facilitate the employee performance assessment process at the West Java branch office.
- Utilized PHP programming language and leveraged the Laravel framework.
- Built a responsive and user-friendly User Interface for the "Employee Performance Management Information System" web application.
- Responsible for deploying the system on the provided hosting, ensuring smooth application operation.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITAS KOMPUTER INDONESIA

Bandung

Bachelor of Computer Science

2018 - 2022

• Major in Informatics Engineering, 3.15 / 4.00

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: PHP, Javascript, CSS, HTML
- Framework: PHP (Laravel), Javascript (React Js, React Native, NodeJS, ExpressJS, NextJs), CSS (Tailwind, Bootstrap)
- Database: MySql, MongoDB
- Developer Tools: Gitlab, GitHub, Postman
- Languages : Bahasa Indonesia (native), English (intermediate)
- Other Relevant Skills: Responsive Slicing UI, REST API, Debugging, Figma, Atomic Design, Teamwork.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi Junior Web Developer (BNSP)
- CCNAv7: Introduction to Networks (CISCO)